ATHARV MISHRA

Android App Developer

+91-8755328239

atharvmishra77@gmail.com

My links:- https://atharv-portfolio-ashy.vercel.app

Noida

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Rising star in WIPRO Q4-2022
- Was part of NIT Rourkela Hacksagon 2023
- Among top Performers in 2023

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

GL Bajaj Group Of Institutions,

Mathura

2017 - 2021

SKILLS

• Languages: Kotlin, Java

• Development Tools: Android Studio

 Frameworks & Libraries: Android Jetpack, Retrofit, Room, Dagger Hilt, Coroutines

• Version Control: Git

 UI/UX Design:Material Design principles, responsive layouts

• CI/CD Pipeline: Jenkins

• Architectures - MVC & MVVM

LANGUAGES

Hindi

· English

OTHER PROJECTS

Hello NITR App (NIT Rourkela)

- Built an app for **NIT Rourkela** that bridges the .communication gap between faculty and students.
- Made sure the app runs smoothly and handles data efficiently.

JCB App

- Also worked on a JCB app as a freelancer, focusing on design, backend, and user authentication.
- Used Java, Android Studio, and Firebase to build a seamless and user-friendly experience.

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ayushgupta.nexa_parts_final<a href="mailto:id=ayushgupta.nexa_parts_final<a href

ABOUT ME

I'm a passionate Android developer with over 3 years of experience in creating mobile applications that enhance the user experience. My expertise lies in developing feature-rich Android apps using *Kotlin* and *Java*, with a strong focus on best practices and user-centric design.

My work: https://atharv-portfolio-ashy.vercel.app/

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Unnati AgriTech (Noida) Feb 2023- Present

Android App Developer

Ora Finance App

- Led end-to-end development of a robust loan application using MVVM architecture, integrating payment gateway, many APIs, E-Mandate, and KYC processes.
- Designed an elegant and intuitive UI, optimized app performance.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, conducted code reviews, and mentored junior developers.
- Followed Best possible Coding Practices which resulted in almost no warnings in entire project.
- Implemented Firebase Crashlytics to stay updated about the App crashes on live

APP LINK: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.app.orafinancecustomer

U-store App (100K+ Downloads)

- Developed, tested and deployed multiple modules.
- · Integrated Payment Gateway and third party SDKs
- Migrated Entire Code-Base from Java to Kotlin .
- · Replaced async calls with Retrofit API.
- Replaced from **SQLite** to **RoomDB** for better data management and user experience.
- Improved overall app speed, functionality, and user satisfaction through thorough testing and optimization.

APP LINK: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?

id=com.unnatiagro.agripos&pcampaignid=web_share

OraFinance Field App

- Led the entitre development of the OraFinance Field App for customer onboarding in loan services.
- Utilized MVVM architecture for a clean and maintainable codebase.
- Implemented Coroutines for efficient background processing.
- · Integrated REST APIs using Retrofit and managed dependencies with Dagger Hilt.
- Enhanced data management with Room Database.
- Streamlined the onboarding process for field agents, improving efficiency and customer interactions.

■ WIPRO Technologies (Gurugram) Aug 2021 - Feb 2023

SDET (Software Development Engineer in Test)

- Designed, developed, and maintained automated test scripts using Java Selenium framework.
- Worked on agile methodology with the help of tools like Jira and Confluenece.
- Integrated automated tests with the **CI/CD** pipeline to ensure continuous testing.
- Ensured that the automation coverage includes functional, regression, performance, and load testing.
- Worked closely with developers to understand the architecture and design of the software.
- Wrote and maintained code to support the development and automation of testing processes.

● LogicLadder Technologies (Gurugram) March 2021 - July 2021

Android App Developer (Intern)

- Contributed to developing an Android app for a sustainability management technology company.
- Worked on **Bluetooth** which collects the data from difference **Sensors**.
- Built user interfaces, integrated APIs.
- Worked under the guidance of senior developers to enhance app functionality.